{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,97],"content":"What to tell your end users about using Intune | Microsoft Intune","needQuote":true,"nodes":[{"content":"What to tell your end users about using Intune | Microsoft Intune","pos":[0,65]}]},{"pos":[111,160],"content":"Links to information to share with your end users","needQuote":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Links to information to share with your end users","pos":[0,49]}]},{"pos":[490,546],"content":"What to tell your end users about using Microsoft Intune","linkify":"What to tell your end users about using Microsoft Intune","nodes":[{"content":"What to tell your end users about using Microsoft Intune","pos":[0,56]}]},{"content":"Use these links and information to:","pos":[548,583]},{"content":"Understand the steps that your users follow to do different tasks in Intune.","pos":[587,663]},{"content":"Give to your users to help them complete tasks and solve issues they have while using Intune.","pos":[666,759]},{"pos":[761,996],"content":"Be sure that you include the IT administrator's contact information when you <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>customize the Company Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](/Intune/get-started/start-with-a-paid-subscription-to-microsoft-intune-step-7)</ept> so that your users can get help if they need it.","source":"Be sure that you include the IT administrator's contact information when you [customize the Company Portal](/Intune/get-started/start-with-a-paid-subscription-to-microsoft-intune-step-7) so that your users can get help if they need it."},{"pos":[1002,1062],"content":"Where your end users can find information about common tasks","linkify":"Where your end users can find information about common tasks","nodes":[{"content":"Where your end users can find information about common tasks","pos":[0,60]}]},{"content":"When enrolled users need help using Intune, they typically see a link in the Company Portal website or Company Portal app that points them to a specific article with steps on how to fix the issue or complete the task.","pos":[1064,1281]},{"content":"For example, if Android users see a message saying that they are missing a required certificate, they can tap a \"How to resolve this\" link to go to an article with steps on how to get the certificate.","pos":[1282,1482]},{"content":"The links below are for IT administrators.","pos":[1485,1527]},{"content":"These pages contain links to all of the articles that users are sent to when from the Company Portal website or app.","pos":[1528,1644]},{"content":"The link are divided into sections: Company Portal app installation and Intune enrollment; tasks that users can do on their devices, like using managed apps and manually syncing their devices; and troubleshooting.","pos":[1645,1858]},{"content":"Using your Android device with Intune","pos":[1863,1900]},{"content":"Using your iOS or Mac OS X device with Intune","pos":[1960,2005]},{"content":"Using your Windows device with Intune","pos":[2073,2110]},{"content":"Using the Intune Company Portal website","pos":[2170,2209]},{"pos":[2273,2342],"content":"Enrollment guides and templates that you can customize for your users","linkify":"Enrollment guides and templates that you can customize for your users","nodes":[{"content":"Enrollment guides and templates that you can customize for your users","pos":[0,69]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Customizable, end-user Intune enrollment template for IT administrators<ept id=\"p1\">](https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/End-user-Intune-enrollment-55dfd64a)</ept> - Customizable Word document with detailed steps and screenshots of end-user enrollment for iOS, Mac OS X, and Android devices.","pos":[2346,2622],"source":"[Customizable, end-user Intune enrollment template for IT administrators](https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/End-user-Intune-enrollment-55dfd64a) - Customizable Word document with detailed steps and screenshots of end-user enrollment for iOS, Mac OS X, and Android devices."},{"content":"You can use this document as is, or you can customize the instructions before giving this document to your end users.","pos":[2623,2740]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Two-page customizable document, with steps and embedded videos on enrolling, unenrolling, getting apps, more<ept id=\"p1\">](https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/Intune-End-User-Enrollment-3a0c9b0c#content)</ept> - Document that you can customize and give to your end users.","pos":[2753,3008],"source":"[Two-page customizable document, with steps and embedded videos on enrolling, unenrolling, getting apps, more](https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/Intune-End-User-Enrollment-3a0c9b0c#content) - Document that you can customize and give to your end users."},{"content":"Has sections on how to enroll Android, iOS, and Windows devices, get apps, unenroll, what to do if you lose your device, and what IT Pros can and can't see on your device.","pos":[3009,3180]},{"pos":[3184,3217],"content":"How your end users get their apps","linkify":"How your end users get their apps","nodes":[{"content":"How your end users get their apps","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"To understand how your end users get their apps, choose from the following device platform options:","pos":[3219,3318]},{"content":"How your Android users get their apps","pos":[3359,3396]},{"content":"How your iOS users get their apps","pos":[3443,3476]},{"content":"How your Windows users get their apps","pos":[3519,3556]},{"pos":[3604,3657],"content":"Help end users understand Company Portal app messages","linkify":"Help end users understand Company Portal app messages","nodes":[{"content":"Help end users understand Company Portal app messages","pos":[0,53]}]},{"pos":[3659,3901],"content":"To help your users solve issues that they might have when they are using the Company Portal, you can review a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>list of messages users might see in the Company Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](/Intune/Plan-Design/help-end-users-understand-company-portal-app-messages)</ept>.","source":"To help your users solve issues that they might have when they are using the Company Portal, you can review a [list of messages users might see in the Company Portal](/Intune/Plan-Design/help-end-users-understand-company-portal-app-messages)."},{"content":"If there is other information that you would like to see covered in this article, please add your suggestion to the Comment box at the bottom of this topic.","pos":[3903,4059]},{"content":"Thanks!","pos":[4060,4067]}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: What to tell your end users about using Intune | Microsoft Intune\ndescription: Links to information to share with your end users\nkeywords:\nauthor: staciebarker\nmanager: angrobe\nms.date: 08/24/2016\nms.topic: get-started-article\nms.prod:\nms.service: microsoft-intune\nms.technology:\nms.assetid: 48914533-f138-4dc0-8b93-4cea3ac61f7b\n\n# optional metadata\n\n#ROBOTS:\n#audience:\n#ms.devlang:\nms.reviewer: jeffgilb\nms.suite: ems\n#ms.tgt_pltfrm:\n#ms.custom:\n\n---\n\n\n\n# What to tell your end users about using Microsoft Intune\n\nUse these links and information to:\n\n- Understand the steps that your users follow to do different tasks in Intune.\n- Give to your users to help them complete tasks and solve issues they have while using Intune.\n\nBe sure that you include the IT administrator's contact information when you [customize the Company Portal](/Intune/get-started/start-with-a-paid-subscription-to-microsoft-intune-step-7) so that your users can get help if they need it.\n\n\n## Where your end users can find information about common tasks\n\nWhen enrolled users need help using Intune, they typically see a link in the Company Portal website or Company Portal app that points them to a specific article with steps on how to fix the issue or complete the task. For example, if Android users see a message saying that they are missing a required certificate, they can tap a \"How to resolve this\" link to go to an article with steps on how to get the certificate. \n\nThe links below are for IT administrators. These pages contain links to all of the articles that users are sent to when from the Company Portal website or app. The link are divided into sections: Company Portal app installation and Intune enrollment; tasks that users can do on their devices, like using managed apps and manually syncing their devices; and troubleshooting.\n\n- [Using your Android device with Intune](/Intune/EndUser/using-your-android-device-with-intune)\n- [Using your iOS or Mac OS X device with Intune](/Intune/EndUser/using-your-ios-or-mac-os-x-device-with-intune)\n- [Using your Windows device with Intune](/Intune/EndUser/using-your-windows-device-with-intune)\n- [Using the Intune Company Portal website](/Intune/EndUser/using-the-intune-company-portal-website)\n\n\n## Enrollment guides and templates that you can customize for your users\n\n- [Customizable, end-user Intune enrollment template for IT administrators](https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/End-user-Intune-enrollment-55dfd64a) - Customizable Word document with detailed steps and screenshots of end-user enrollment for iOS, Mac OS X, and Android devices. You can use this document as is, or you can customize the instructions before giving this document to your end users.</br></br>\n- [Two-page customizable document, with steps and embedded videos on enrolling, unenrolling, getting apps, more](https://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/Intune-End-User-Enrollment-3a0c9b0c#content) - Document that you can customize and give to your end users. Has sections on how to enroll Android, iOS, and Windows devices, get apps, unenroll, what to do if you lose your device, and what IT Pros can and can't see on your device.\n\n##How your end users get their apps\n\nTo understand how your end users get their apps, choose from the following device platform options:\n\n> [!div class=\"op_single_selector\"]\n- [How your Android users get their apps](how-your-android-users-get-their-apps.md)\n- [How your iOS users get their apps](how-your-ios-users-get-their-apps.md)\n- [How your Windows users get their apps](how-your-windows-users-get-their-apps.md)\n\n## Help end users understand Company Portal app messages\n\nTo help your users solve issues that they might have when they are using the Company Portal, you can review a [list of messages users might see in the Company Portal](/Intune/Plan-Design/help-end-users-understand-company-portal-app-messages).\n\nIf there is other information that you would like to see covered in this article, please add your suggestion to the Comment box at the bottom of this topic. Thanks!\n"}