{"nodes":[{"pos":[13,24],"content":"Whitepapers","needQuote":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Whitepapers","pos":[0,11]}]},{"pos":[57,71],"content":"powershell,DSC","needQuote":true,"nodes":[{"content":"powershell,DSC","pos":[0,14]}]},{"content":"Whitepapers","pos":[169,180]},{"content":"The following whitepapers have been published to provide additional information on topics related to PowerShell Desired State Configuration.","pos":[182,322]},{"content":"The Release Pipeline Model","pos":[327,353]},{"content":"There are benefits to be gained when patterns and practices from developer techniques are applied to operations.","pos":[354,466]},{"content":"Notably, a fully automated solution where infrastructure is managed as code and all changes are automatically validated before reaching production.","pos":[467,614]},{"content":"This is a process shift that is recognized among industry innovators.","pos":[615,684]},{"content":"For organizations already leveraging these processes, it should be clear how to leverage Microsoft platforms.","pos":[685,794]},{"content":"For organizations that are new to the topic, it should be clear how to bring this process to your environment and what it means to your organizational culture.","pos":[795,954]},{"content":"This document explains the components of a Release Pipeline for configuration as code, the value to operations, and solutions that are used when designing a new Release Pipeline architecture.","pos":[955,1146]},{"pos":[1149,1209],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Download PDF<ept id=\"p2\">](http://aka.ms/thereleasepipelinemodelpdf)</ept><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**[Download PDF](http://aka.ms/thereleasepipelinemodelpdf)**"}],"content":"---\ntitle:   Whitepapers\nms.date:  2016-05-16\nkeywords:  powershell,DSC\ndescription:  \nms.topic:  article\nauthor:  eslesar\nmanager:  dongill\nms.prod:  powershell\n---\n\n# Whitepapers\n\nThe following whitepapers have been published to provide additional information on topics related to PowerShell Desired State Configuration.\n\n## The Release Pipeline Model\nThere are benefits to be gained when patterns and practices from developer techniques are applied to operations. Notably, a fully automated solution where infrastructure is managed as code and all changes are automatically validated before reaching production. This is a process shift that is recognized among industry innovators. For organizations already leveraging these processes, it should be clear how to leverage Microsoft platforms. For organizations that are new to the topic, it should be clear how to bring this process to your environment and what it means to your organizational culture. This document explains the components of a Release Pipeline for configuration as code, the value to operations, and solutions that are used when designing a new Release Pipeline architecture. \n\n**[Download PDF](http://aka.ms/thereleasepipelinemodelpdf)**\n\n"}