{"nodes":[{"pos":[32,72],"content":"Protect apps and data | Microsoft Intune","needQuote":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Protect apps and data | Microsoft Intune","pos":[0,40]}]},{"pos":[96,231],"content":"This topic describes the various Intune features and capabilities that are available to you to help protect your company apps and data.","needQuote":true,"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes the various Intune features and capabilities that are available to you to help protect your company apps and data.","pos":[0,135]}]},{"content":"Protect apps and data with Microsoft Intune","pos":[538,581]},{"content":"Intune protects company data through multiple technology layers.","pos":[584,648]},{"content":"At the identity layer, conditional access protects access to services by only allowing access from managed and compliant devices.","pos":[650,779]},{"content":"At the client application layer, mobile app management (MAM)  protects data loss by preventing data from moving to non-protected apps or storage locations and by wiping data when a device is lost or stolen.","pos":[781,987]},{"content":"These two layers of protection should be used together in order to secure data while keeping your mobile workforce productive.","pos":[989,1115]},{"content":"An important first step to protecting company data is to implement conditional access by making sure that devices used to access that data are using security protections like strong password, encryption, and are not jailbroken.","pos":[1117,1344]},{"content":"Microsoft Intune gives you the ability to set conditions that the devices have to comply with, before they are allowed to access your company email and data.","pos":[1345,1502]},{"pos":[1504,1655],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Conditional access<ept id=\"p1\">](restrict-access-to-email-and-o365-services-with-microsoft-intune.md)</ept> is determined by two types of policies you can set in Intune:","source":"[Conditional access](restrict-access-to-email-and-o365-services-with-microsoft-intune.md) is determined by two types of policies you can set in Intune:"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Compliance policies<ept id=\"p1\">](introduction-to-device-compliance-policies-in-microsoft-intune.md)</ept> determine the compliance of a device.","pos":[1658,1784],"source":"[Compliance policies](introduction-to-device-compliance-policies-in-microsoft-intune.md) determine the compliance of a device."},{"content":"They evaluate settings and conditions like:","pos":[1785,1828]},{"content":"PIN and passwords: You can create rules to require passwords before unlocking a device, the complexity requirements of the password, and other password settings.","pos":[1833,1994]},{"content":"Encryption: You can restrict access to devices that are encrypted.","pos":[1999,2065]},{"content":"Device is not jailbroken or rooted: Intune can detect if an enrolled device is jailbroken, and you can set the policy to block access on such devices.","pos":[2070,2220]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Conditional access policies<ept id=\"p1\">](restrict-access-to-email-and-o365-services-with-microsoft-intune.md)</ept> are configured for a particular service like Exchange Online or SharePoint Online.","pos":[2223,2404],"source":"[Conditional access policies](restrict-access-to-email-and-o365-services-with-microsoft-intune.md) are configured for a particular service like Exchange Online or SharePoint Online."},{"content":"For each service, you can define which groups of users these policies should apply to.","pos":[2405,2491]},{"content":"For example, you can make sure that everyone in the finance department can only access company email from enrolled and compliant devices.","pos":[2492,2629]},{"content":"Securing access to company resources is just the first step to protecting company data.","pos":[2631,2718]},{"content":"You still need the ability to protect the data once it has been accessed on the device.","pos":[2719,2806]},{"content":"The data can now be copied, moved, saved to a different location, or shared.","pos":[2807,2883]},{"content":"Intune solves this problem by providing you with the ability to restrict data movement by creating a set of rules like:","pos":[2884,3003]},{"content":"Block copy and paste, or prevent data transfer outside of the work context.","pos":[3006,3081]},{"content":"Prevent backup to personal cloud storage, prevent Save as.","pos":[3084,3142]},{"content":"Secure app access by requiring PIN/passcode or corporate credentials.","pos":[3145,3214]},{"content":"Have all web links open within the Intune Managed Browser.","pos":[3217,3275]},{"content":"These set of rules are referred to as <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>mobile app management (MAM) policies<ept id=\"p1\">](protect-app-data-using-mobile-app-management-policies-with-microsoft-intune.md)</ept>.","pos":[3277,3434],"source":"These set of rules are referred to as [mobile app management (MAM) policies](protect-app-data-using-mobile-app-management-policies-with-microsoft-intune.md)."},{"content":"MAM policies can be applied to apps running on devices that may or may not be managed by you.","pos":[3436,3529]},{"pos":[3533,3791],"content":"You can protect your company data using MAM policies for devices that are <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>enrolled in Intune<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, devices that are <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>enrolled and managed by another third party MDM<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or a device that is <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>not enrolled in any MDM solution<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, like the employee owned devices.","source":"You can protect your company data using MAM policies for devices that are **enrolled in Intune**, devices that are **enrolled and managed by another third party MDM**, or a device that is **not enrolled in any MDM solution**, like the employee owned devices."},{"content":"To associate an app with a MAM policy, the app must incorporate the Microsoft Intune App Software Development Kit (SDK), or use the App wrapping tool.","pos":[3793,3943]},{"content":"Apps like Microsoft Office apps have the App SDK built-in.","pos":[3945,4003]},{"content":"The full list of supported apps can be found on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Intune mobile application gallery<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/microsoft-intune/partners.aspx)</ept> in the Microsoft Intune application partners page.","pos":[4004,4238],"source":" The full list of supported apps can be found on the [Microsoft Intune mobile application gallery](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/microsoft-intune/partners.aspx) in the Microsoft Intune application partners page."},{"content":"Choose the app to see the supported scenarios, platforms and whether or not the app supports multi-identity.","pos":[4239,4347]},{"pos":[4349,4523],"content":"You can also <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>enable your custom built line of business apps<ept id=\"p1\">](decide-how-to-prepare-apps-for-mobile-application-management-with-microsoft-intune.md)</ept> to use with MAM policies.","source":"You can also [enable your custom built line of business apps](decide-how-to-prepare-apps-for-mobile-application-management-with-microsoft-intune.md) to use with MAM policies."},{"pos":[4525,4786],"content":"In addition to restricting data movement, if a device gets lost or stolen, or if the user is no longer working with your company, you can <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>selectively wipe company data<ept id=\"p1\">](wipe-managed-company-app-data-with-microsoft-intune.md)</ept>, leaving only personal data behind.","source":"In addition to restricting data movement, if a device gets lost or stolen, or if the user is no longer working with your company, you can [selectively wipe company data](wipe-managed-company-app-data-with-microsoft-intune.md), leaving only personal data behind."}],"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Protect apps and data | Microsoft Intune\ndescription:\nkeywords: This topic describes the various Intune features and capabilities that are available to you to help protect your company apps and data.\nauthor: karthikaraman\nmanager: angrobe\nms.date: 07/18/2016\nms.topic: article\nms.prod:\nms.service: microsoft-intune\nms.technology:\nms.assetid: 5c46e188-87eb-4ce2-b184-24809e8bf783\n\n# optional metadata\n\n#ROBOTS:\n#audience:\n#ms.devlang:\nms.reviewer: chrisgre\nms.suite: ems\n#ms.tgt_pltfrm:\n#ms.custom:\n\n---\n\n# Protect apps and data with Microsoft Intune\n\n\nIntune protects company data through multiple technology layers.  At the identity layer, conditional access protects access to services by only allowing access from managed and compliant devices.  At the client application layer, mobile app management (MAM)  protects data loss by preventing data from moving to non-protected apps or storage locations and by wiping data when a device is lost or stolen.  These two layers of protection should be used together in order to secure data while keeping your mobile workforce productive.\n\nAn important first step to protecting company data is to implement conditional access by making sure that devices used to access that data are using security protections like strong password, encryption, and are not jailbroken. Microsoft Intune gives you the ability to set conditions that the devices have to comply with, before they are allowed to access your company email and data.\n\n[Conditional access](restrict-access-to-email-and-o365-services-with-microsoft-intune.md) is determined by two types of policies you can set in Intune:\n- [Compliance policies](introduction-to-device-compliance-policies-in-microsoft-intune.md) determine the compliance of a device. They evaluate settings and conditions like:\n  - PIN and passwords: You can create rules to require passwords before unlocking a device, the complexity requirements of the password, and other password settings.\n  - Encryption: You can restrict access to devices that are encrypted.\n  - Device is not jailbroken or rooted: Intune can detect if an enrolled device is jailbroken, and you can set the policy to block access on such devices.\n- [Conditional access policies](restrict-access-to-email-and-o365-services-with-microsoft-intune.md) are configured for a particular service like Exchange Online or SharePoint Online. For each service, you can define which groups of users these policies should apply to. For example, you can make sure that everyone in the finance department can only access company email from enrolled and compliant devices.\n\nSecuring access to company resources is just the first step to protecting company data. You still need the ability to protect the data once it has been accessed on the device. The data can now be copied, moved, saved to a different location, or shared. Intune solves this problem by providing you with the ability to restrict data movement by creating a set of rules like:\n- Block copy and paste, or prevent data transfer outside of the work context.\n- Prevent backup to personal cloud storage, prevent Save as.\n- Secure app access by requiring PIN/passcode or corporate credentials.\n- Have all web links open within the Intune Managed Browser.\n\nThese set of rules are referred to as [mobile app management (MAM) policies](protect-app-data-using-mobile-app-management-policies-with-microsoft-intune.md).  MAM policies can be applied to apps running on devices that may or may not be managed by you.  \n\nYou can protect your company data using MAM policies for devices that are **enrolled in Intune**, devices that are **enrolled and managed by another third party MDM**, or a device that is **not enrolled in any MDM solution**, like the employee owned devices.\n\nTo associate an app with a MAM policy, the app must incorporate the Microsoft Intune App Software Development Kit (SDK), or use the App wrapping tool.\n\nApps like Microsoft Office apps have the App SDK built-in. The full list of supported apps can be found on the [Microsoft Intune mobile application gallery](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/products/microsoft-intune/partners.aspx) in the Microsoft Intune application partners page. Choose the app to see the supported scenarios, platforms and whether or not the app supports multi-identity.\n\nYou can also [enable your custom built line of business apps](decide-how-to-prepare-apps-for-mobile-application-management-with-microsoft-intune.md) to use with MAM policies.\n\nIn addition to restricting data movement, if a device gets lost or stolen, or if the user is no longer working with your company, you can [selectively wipe company data](wipe-managed-company-app-data-with-microsoft-intune.md), leaving only personal data behind.\n"}