{"nodes":[{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Port Mirrored Domain Controllers (FQDN)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (required for the ATA Gateway, this cannot be changed for the ATA Lightweight Gateway): Enter the complete FQDN of your domain controller and click the plus sign to add it to the list.","pos":[4,232],"source":"**Port Mirrored Domain Controllers (FQDN)** (required for the ATA Gateway, this cannot be changed for the ATA Lightweight Gateway): Enter the complete FQDN of your domain controller and click the plus sign to add it to the list."},{"content":"For example,  <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>dc01.contoso.com<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[233,267],"source":" For example,  **dc01.contoso.com**"},{"content":"All domain controllers whose traffic is being monitored via port mirroring by the ATA Gateway must be listed in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Domain Controllers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> list.","pos":[385,529],"source":"All domain controllers whose traffic is being monitored via port mirroring by the ATA Gateway must be listed in the **Domain Controllers** list."},{"content":"If a domain controller is not listed in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Domain Controllers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> list, detection of suspicious activities might not function as expected.","pos":[530,669],"source":" If a domain controller is not listed in the **Domain Controllers** list, detection of suspicious activities might not function as expected."},{"content":"At least one domain controller in the list should be a global catalog.","pos":[681,751]},{"content":"This will enable ATA to resolve computer and user objects in other domains in the forest.","pos":[752,841]}],"content":"  - **Port Mirrored Domain Controllers (FQDN)** (required for the ATA Gateway, this cannot be changed for the ATA Lightweight Gateway): Enter the complete FQDN of your domain controller and click the plus sign to add it to the list. For example,  **dc01.contoso.com** \n\n        The following information applies to the servers you enter in the **Domain Controllers** list: \n\n        - All domain controllers whose traffic is being monitored via port mirroring by the ATA Gateway must be listed in the **Domain Controllers** list. If a domain controller is not listed in the **Domain Controllers** list, detection of suspicious activities might not function as expected. \n        - At least one domain controller in the list should be a global catalog. This will enable ATA to resolve computer and user objects in other domains in the forest. \n"}