{"nodes":[{"content":"Build Custom Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources Test6 - test","pos":[2,84]},{"content":"Applies To: Windows PowerShell 4.0, Windows PowerShell 5.0","pos":[88,146]},{"content":"Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration (DSC) has built-in resources that you can use to configure your environment.","pos":[148,271]},{"content":"(For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Built-In Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources<ept id=\"p1\">](builtInResource.md)</ept>.) This topic provides an overview of developing resources and links to topics with specific information and examples.","pos":[272,504],"source":" (For more information, see [Built-In Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources](builtInResource.md).) This topic provides an overview of developing resources and links to topics with specific information and examples."},{"content":"DSC resource components","pos":[509,532]},{"content":"A DSC resource is a Windows PowerShell module.","pos":[534,580]},{"content":"The module contains both the schema (the definition of the configurable properties) and the implementation (the code that does the actual work specified by a configuration) for the resource.","pos":[581,771]},{"content":"A DSC resource schema can be defined in a MOF file, and the implementation is performed by a script module.","pos":[772,879]},{"content":"Beginning with the support of PowerShell classes in version 5, the schema and implementation can both be defined in a class.","pos":[880,1004]},{"content":"The following topics describe in more detail how to create DSC resources.","pos":[1005,1078]},{"content":"Writing a custom DSC resource with MOF","pos":[1083,1121]},{"content":"Implementing a DSC resource in C","pos":[1152,1184]},{"content":"Writing a custom DSC resource with PowerShell classes","pos":[1218,1271]},{"content":"Composite resources: Using a DSC configuration as a resource","pos":[1304,1364]},{"content":"Using the Resource Designer tool","pos":[1401,1433]}],"content":"# Build Custom Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources Test6 - test\n\n> Applies To: Windows PowerShell 4.0, Windows PowerShell 5.0\n\nWindows PowerShell Desired State Configuration (DSC) has built-in resources that you can use to configure your environment. (For more information, see [Built-In Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources](builtInResource.md).) This topic provides an overview of developing resources and links to topics with specific information and examples.\n\n## DSC resource components\n\nA DSC resource is a Windows PowerShell module. The module contains both the schema (the definition of the configurable properties) and the implementation (the code that does the actual work specified by a configuration) for the resource. A DSC resource schema can be defined in a MOF file, and the implementation is performed by a script module. Beginning with the support of PowerShell classes in version 5, the schema and implementation can both be defined in a class. The following topics describe in more detail how to create DSC resources.\n\n* [Writing a custom DSC resource with MOF](authoringResourceMOF.md) \n* [Implementing a DSC resource in C#](authoringResourceMofCS.md) \n* [Writing a custom DSC resource with PowerShell classes](authoringResourceClass.md) \n* [Composite resources: Using a DSC configuration as a resource](authoringResourceComposite.md) \n* [Using the Resource Designer tool](authoringResourceMofDesigner.md) \n"}